# RAYMUNDO HERNANDEZ

Chicago, IL 60625 | (773) 957-4849 | Rjhern37@neiu.edu

GitHub - Rjhern37

# **Professional Summary**

Solution-driven professional who excels in collaborative work environments while focusing on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and MERN stack development. Experience building products for desktop, phone and mobile app users, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience and speed. Translates solutions into code and works across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases. Special talent for communication and project management backed by training in Business Management.

## **Education**

## **Bachelor of Science: Business Management**

Digital Marketing, International Marketing, Marketing Research Northeastern Illinois University (NEIU) Chicago, IL

## Certifications

2020 Full Stack Web Development from Northwestern University

Evanston, IL

2018

# **Web Development and Technical Skills**

- JavaScript
- HTML and XML
- **Programming Languages**
- **CSS React**
- **REST**
- API design knowledge
- Agile workflow processes
- Web user interfaces

- Microsoft Office programs
- Google apps
- Survey Monkey
- Social Media Management
- Adobe Photoshop
- Design patterns and principles
- Algorithm Implementation

- Case management
- Database Management
- Data collection and analysis
- Software best practices
- File Management
- Testing and maintenance
- Technical analysis
- Website optimization

# **RAYMUNDO HERNANDEZ**

Chicago, IL 60625 | (773) 957-4849 | Rihern37@neiu.edu

GitHub - Rjhern37

# **Work History**

#### **Guest Experience Manager**

Aug 2012 - Current

**Amazing Ventures** 

Chicago, IL

- Promoted to Manager from Cashier after showing exceptional customer service and leadership skills
- Perform managerial open/close duties, including cash management, reconciliation, store operations and lead shift teams of 4-6 employees
- Resolve any customer complaints with patience and understanding, used quick response and dynamic service skills to build relationships with patrons, improving customer retention rate
- Assist in staff hiring and training, as well as help organize customer and staff events, including: The "Haunted Maze", which resulted in greater brand exposure and additional revenue not typical of that season

### **Customer Service Representative**

Apr 2011 - Apr 2012

The Sports Authority

Chicago, IL

- Greeted and assisted customers with their purchases
- Assisted with store operations and cleaning.
- Answered customer telephone calls promptly to avoid on-hold wait times.
- Recommended various products and services to customers, thoroughly explaining details.

#### **Affiliations**

ALPFA (Association of Latino Professionals for America) Chicago, Member, 2019-Present